

PROFILE

I bring a vast knowledge base, from a wide range of experiences, to add value to my clients' in ways that consistently exceed expectations. I communication skills, with analytical skills, and leadership to contribute to my teams success. I have demonstrated good acumen in developing and leading with successful ventures in both.

PERSONAL SKILLS

Communication (Public Speaking Innovative Teamwork C++ Python SOL Adobe Suite MS Office

INFO



Address

Brampton, ON Canada



Phone

(226) 980-5036



Email



Website



Github

github.com/rheera

RAMAN HEERA

DEVELOPER



WORK EXPERIENCE



SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN | ROBARTS RESEARCH INST. 2017-2018

- Worked on creating a Slicer module capable of replicating X-ray results, for surgeons to practice virtual spinal interventions, without using fluoroscopy.
- Eliminates exposure to radiation during training.
- Uses an optical tracker to capture the spine model, the needle, and the virtual fluoroscope camera head in 3D space with minimal input lag.
- Created in-depth documentation for future developers to work on the project as well as for anyone looking to use it.
- Created the module using CPP within Visual Studio.

CO-FOUNDER | DAPPER BLVD. 2015-2019

- Co-founded a men's accessory e-commerce boutique.
- Responsible for marketing, such as making sure the website and social media are aesthetically pleasing and running smoothly.
- Also delegated tasks, filling all roles myself when needed, such as: ordering products in bulk, innovating designs, assembling merchandise, establishing and maintaining customer relations.
- Effective written and oral communication with partners and clients.



EDUCATION



Dean's Honour List

London, ON | April 2018 UNIVERSITY OF WESTERN ONTARIO **B.Sc IN COMPUTER SCIENCE** MINOR IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING



CERTIFCATIONS



SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT | AMAZON WEB SERVICES. 2020-2023 Associate



PROJECTS



TEAM LEAD | NVIZION. 2016-2017

- Collaboration Project with Schulich School of Medicine and Dentistry
- Completely updated and revamped an employee organization system for Schulich.
- Added visualization features such as graphs and sorting methods for quick reduction in data.
- Created a lucid install and user guide; as well as a detailed report with all features, deliverables, design patterns, and use cases.
- Created using CPP.

DEVELOPER | NBA Stats to Redefine Player Roles. 2018

- Created a script using Selenium in Python to scrape data from a Basketball Reference website and input the data into an SQL database
- Used the data to weigh different statistics and create new positions, rather than just the traditional five positions.
- Using these positions and stats we could find better team compositions.
- Created using Python and SQL